Seaspiracy is a documentary, crime film directed by Ali Tabrizi.
Passionate about ocean life, a filmmaker sets out to document the harm that humans
do to marine species — and uncovers an alarming global conspiracy.
Self, played by Ali Tabrizi.
Self, played by Sylvia Earle.
Self, played by Richard O'Barry.
Self, played by Paul de Gelder.
Self, played by Lucy Tabrizi.
Self, played by Jonathan Balcombe.
Seaspiracy () is a 2021 documentary film about the environmental impact of
fishing directed by and starring Ali Tabrizi, a British filmmaker.
The film examines human impacts on marine life and
advocates for ending fish consumption.
The film explores environmental issues affecting oceans, including plastic pollution, ghost nets and
overfishing, and argues that commercial fisheries are the main driver of marine ecosystem destruction.
The film rejects the concept of sustainable fishing and criticises several marine conservation organisations, including the Earth
Island Institute and its dolphin safe label and the sustainable seafood certifications of the Marine Stewardship Council.
It also criticises efforts by organisations to reduce household
plastic, contrasting their impact with that of ghost nets.
It accuses these initiatives of being a cover-up for the environmental
impact of fishing and corruption in the fishing industry.
Seaspiracy concludes by supporting marine reserves
and for ending fish consumption.
The film was produced by Kip Andersen, director of the documentary
Cowspiracy, and used the same production team as this previous film.
Initial financial support was provided by British entrepreneur
Dale Vince, and it was acquired by Netflix in 2020.
The film premiered on Netflix globally in March 2021 and
garnered immediate attention in several countries.
The film received mixed reviews; reviewers praised it for bringing attention to its subject matter,
but it was accused of scientific inaccuracy and was criticised by some ocean experts.
Organisations and individuals interviewed or negatively portrayed in the film
disputed its assertions and accused the film of misrepresenting them.
Seaspiracy also prompted responses from other environmental organisations, academics and seafood
industry groups, and several media outlets fact-checked certain statements in the film.
The film explores themes of pollution, fishing,
ecology, vegan, environmental destruction.
The tone is thought_provoking.